Nobody cares what you think anymore.
>> Actors, love them or hate them, they
just will Love them or hate them, they
just will not go away. They've existed
since the earliest days of human
civilization when Greeks and Romans
would gather around to watch them
perform. And today, they're in virtually
every form of entertainment we consume.
Well, until our AI overlords finally
assume control of everything and replace
them with perfect digital replicas.
>> Perfect.
>> Some are performers of superlative skill
and commitment. Others are chosen for
their unusual looks or personalities,
their great beauty, or
their Instagram following.
>> Either way
>> acting tends to bring with it a degree
of fame and attention. And the higher
their star rises, the more of both
they'll get lavished on them. And this
is where the problems can begin, dear
viewer. See, as much as failure and
hardship builds character, success and
adulation reveals it. Some manage to
remain humble and professional, well
aware of their role and what's expected
of them. Others shun the public
spotlight altogether, preferring to keep
their opinions and private lives to
themselves and let their performances do
the talking.
>> This is what streaming does to these
people.
>> Is that, you know, power doesn't
necessarily change you, but it lets you
be who you really are.
And I think that whenever you give a
person money, power, and a lot of
autonomy, they have the ability to
either be a good person or a bad person.
>> While others are able to parlay their
fame and success into billion-dollar
business empires, turning their own
identity into a brand to be marketed.
Those are all fine in their own ways, I
guess, and I don't have a problem with
it.
>> Yeah.
>> If you want to keep to yourself when
you're off the clock, then that's your
right. If you want to make money and
people are willing to hand it over to
you, then go for it, man. But there is
another kind of actor, dear viewer, a
kind that used to be fairly rare until
pretty recently when the world of the
internet and social media and instant
24-hour access to their fan base somehow
fried the parts of their brains that
used to be able to differentiate good
ideas from bad, convinced them they were
more than just good-looking meat puppets
saying words written by someone else,
and that the world desperately needed to
hear their often uninformed groupthink
opinions on absolutely everything from
geopolitics to the economy, military
conflicts, hot-topic social issues, and
even who they should vote for in the
next election.
>> I love how he's just yelling.
I don't even know what it is.
>> guys. Hi, Avengers.
>> Hi, Scarlett.
>> jumping on the call.
>> Whoa, whoa, whoa. I think you mean
assembling.
>> [__] off, Avengers cast. You know, I
never really
>> did the Avengers came together to try to
get Kamala Harris elected.
They did. I feel like, you know what
really killed the mystique and the
morality and like the absolute kind of
glamour of Hollywood was Harvey
Weinstein. That's what really put the
nail in the coffin. And after Harvey
Weinstein happened, I felt like
afterwards, we had a huge huge amount of
people that no longer respected or
wanted to hear what anybody from
Hollywood ever said. Because one of the
things about Harvey Weinstein that was
interesting is that everybody knew that
this was happening.
I think that's kind of what the main
thing about that that made it so kind of
compelling was is that every single
person probably had some kind of idea
that this was happening, but nobody said
anything about it. And I think that
rubbed a lot of people the wrong way
after they just spent being having
spending a decade being evangelized by
these people.
That's why they've really been negative.
Cosby, too. Well, he was an individual.
Like Harvey Weinstein was a lot more
connected.
>> noticed this before, but they look so
plain and washed out and ordinary when
they don't have their professional hair
stylists and makeup artists around to
tart them up. What can I say, man?
Reality can often be disappointing. I'm
talking, of course, about the rise of
the activist actor. Possibly the most
insufferable and deluded of all
celebrity creatures. The population of
activist actors in Hollywood used to be
critically small, existing only in
scattered groups and rarely venturing
out in public, but it skyrocketed over
the past decade, driven by an insatiable
need for online validation, the approval
of their fellow meat puppets, and their
own thinly disguised hatred of anyone
who thinks differently from them. Now,
just before I go on to skewer them
properly, a quick word from today's
sponsor. You don't have to listen to it,
and you're free to skip it, but just
know I appreciate you if you do.
>> off of Hollywood. Yeah, every everybody
everybody knew about Harvey Weinstein,
bro. They all knew about it, and they
all kept quiet because they all wanted
to keep their job. And after that, I
feel like the amount of like moral
authority they had went to zero.
>> Who?
>> They did.
>> Now, much like yourself, I've been known
to frequent the internet from time to
time. And just like you, I've discovered
it can be a dangerous place with all
those absolute scoundrels out to steal
your data, spy on you, and generally
make life unpleasant. That is why you
need Surfshark to take care of all your
online security needs. Want to browse
shopping sites without all those
annoying tracking ads following you
everywhere? No problem. Surfshark's ad
blocker stops tracking cookies and
personalized ads, meaning you get the
browsing experience that you want.
Getting bombarded by scam emails? Then
fear not, because Surfshark scam checker
automatically scans incoming emails for
known scams and fishing attempts.
Worried about your financial information
falling into the wrong hands? Well, not
anymore, because Surfshark automatically
encrypts your personal data, uses
network-level security, and even
proactively monitors for external
threats, making sure your money stays
exactly where it's supposed to be. With
one account, you can install and use
Surfshark on as many devices as you want
to make sure you're protected at all
times. And the best part is their 30-day
money-back guarantee that gives you
plenty of time to try it out. If somehow
you're not satisfied, you can cancel
your subscription and get your money
back, no hassle. Go to
surfshark.com/drinker
and use code drinker at checkout to get
four extra months of Surfshark. What are
you waiting for? Go now.
Okay, let's move on. There are many
examples these days, but the reason I
bring it up specifically is because
former She-Hulk actress Tatiana Maslany,
remember her, recently did a sit-down
podcast interview where she aired her
thoughts on activism in Hollywood and
her opinion of celebrities who prefer to
stay out of the whole thing and just do
their jobs.
>> Tom Selleck,
uh the legendary TV actor, Magnum P.I.
But he said, "Look, I don't dabble in
politics because
uh if I don't understand why you want to
piss off half the country if your job is
entertaining the country." What And then
Michael Jordan used to say like when he
said, "Uh Republicans buy shoes, too.
Our job is to entertain people. It's not
to kind of get involved in this stuff."
What's your response to that?
>> Uh but but all of it is political. Like
everything is political. All
entertainment is political because it
has a viewpoint.
>> I have an IQ of 48 and
and what some people call mentally
[__]
>> I mean, I could point out here that
Michael Jordan's an athlete, not an
artist. And that Tom Selleck is way more
famous, beloved, and successful than
you'll ever be, Tatiana. But hey, you
don't need me
>> People say everything is political
because and in a way they're right.
Everything kind of is political. But
whenever they say everything is
political, what they're trying to really
say is that I want to use that as an
excuse so I can force my social issue
down your throat in this movie. Whereas
whenever somebody says everything's
political, it's about, you know, good
triumphing over evil in Lord of the
Rings. Like yes, almost everything has a
political angle to it. And so the real
problem isn't that your content is
political, it's that your politics are
odious, annoying, not popular, and
everybody hates them.
That's the That's the real issue. Nobody
has a problem with Metal Gear Solid.
Nobody had a problem with Death
Stranding. Nobody had a problem with
Metaphor: ReFantazio. Nobody had a
problem with any of these games because
they were good. The problem isn't
politics. The problem is slop.
>> To tell you that.
>> That's really what it is.
>> would be easy to dunk on Maslany herself
as an aging bitter failed star who blew
her one shot at the big time with one of
the most hilariously disastrous shows in
Marvel history, pitched a hissy fit that
got her rejected from the
>> by the way, yeah, she is being
interviewed by Mehdi Hasan, who all he
wants to do is emotionally blackmail
people into accepting terrorist
propaganda.
That's all he's trying to do.
So that's why he's having her on, asking
this question, wearing a save Gaza shirt
on the [__] Yeah, how about save Gaza
from Hamas? You know, like wearing it as
like it's Star Wars. Like that that's
what the real goal is here.
>> forever and burned most of her bridges
in Hollywood, and has since aged out of
the industry, and is now facing a slow
painful descent into obscurity. I could
do that, but I won't. Not in this video
at least, because there's a bigger issue
at play here, and that issue is summed
up perfectly by her sentiments in this
little segment, which pretty much
encapsulates the mindset of every
activist actor in Hollywood.
>> Artists are like
mirrors to the world, to society.
>> So, I thought to myself, why not take a
few minutes to break it down and see if
we can't draw some conclusions from it.
Ready? Tough [__] because we're about
to start. So, right off the bat, I can
see that she's operating under the false
assumption of what actors are and what
their role actually is. Because here's
an uncomfortable truth for you. Actors,
in and of themselves, are not artists.
They're performers.
Truth nuke.
Oh my god.
Absolute truth nuke.
You're not an artist, you're a
performer.
Wow.
Holy [__] that's bad.
They are instruments who interpret
pieces of art, i.e. the script, usually
within a very narrow framework defined
by the director. In the same way that a
construction worker isn't an architect
because they don't conceive and design
buildings themselves. So, the role of an
actor isn't to create works of art, it's
to perform them to the best of their
abilities. Now, that's not to downplay
the expertise involved in what they do
or anything. Acting can be a challenging
job, and the best actors are rightfully
praised for their skill and commitment
to a role. But, the key difference is
that they're not being praised for their
artistic vision. They're being praised
for their ability to bring someone
else's artistic vision to life. They
themselves create nothing. Now, that can
probably be an
>> I think that there's there there's like
exceptions to this, and there's ways
that you would say like, I mean, you
know, like Henry Cavill with The
Witcher. But, keep in mind that what
happened What was the end result with
Henry Cavill and the and The Witcher?
He's gone.
He's gone. Because Cuz the end of the
day, it's the studio, the director, the
producer, they're the ones that are
making the movie.
That's it. And then yeah, and and you
obviously have like there's other
exceptions where it's like uh Mel Gibson
that are directors, right? But yeah, in
general like yeah, sure. Uh Sylvester
Stallone, another good one.
>> A pleasant realization for a lot of
actors, especially famous ones who are
surrounded by yes men that bombard them
with relentless positivity and probably
fancy themselves as boundless fountains
of creative energy. The unfortunate
truth is most of them are not
particularly creative people. And if you
ask them to write a screenplay or a
novel purely based on their own
imagination, most of them would fail
spectacularly. The realization that
they're nothing more than attractive
meat puppets getting paid embarrassing
amounts of money to dance to someone
else's tune is understandably kind of
horrifying to them. Which is why I think
so many of them turn to activism to fill
that creative and intellectual gap. It
allows them to create
>> Jesus, he's really going in.
This is wow.
>> The illusion, however misplaced, that
there's more to them as individuals than
just looking good while saying lines on
screen. They want to be seen as
something deeper, something more
thoughtful and wise than just another
vacuous performer. And activism not only
allows them to do it, it allows them to
morally grandstand over others at the
same time.
>> probably like there's like an there's
like a level of like misplaced guilt
that I think a lot of people have that
are successful where they see how
successful they are and they realize
that I don't really deserve this and
then they think to themselves, well, I
have to do something in order to offset
my guilt for living this lifestyle that
I don't think I deserve, which is I
think another psychological like effect
of why they're doing this. It's so they
can offset guilt. It's imposter
syndrome. Yeah, I mean there's
definitely a bit of that. And I think
also they can, right? A lot of people
would do this if they could do this.
>> elevating themselves to the level of
enlightened benevolent guides trying
their best to shepherd the ignorant
masses of humanity towards a better
future.
>> Really?
>> Such is their fantasy. But okay, for the
sake of argument, let's give Tatiana a
break here and broaden this discussion
out to artists in general because this
is where it gets really interesting
where the interviewer dares to suggest
that maybe the purpose of art and
artists is to entertain people instead
of lecturing them.
>> But but all of it is political. Like
everything is political. All
entertainment is political because it
has a viewpoint and it has
it has a perspective. It has
visual representation of the world we
live in or the kinds of things that are
funny or acceptable or the ways that
people relate to each other.
>> Well, we all knew this was coming.
>> I mean this is you're painting with such
a broad brush that everything is like
that. Like what these people do is they
paint with such a broad brush like this
so they can justify enforcing their
politics into your media.
That's what they really want to do.
>> old all art is political argument which
funnily enough
>> Like I mean there's very clearly a big
difference between like a Michael Moore
movie for example versus like uh
I don't know
um
a Seth Rogen movie.
I mean really. Like I mean there's
clearly a political difference here.
And if you can't draw that difference
you're just a [__] idiot. And you're
you're you're not an idiot, you're just
lying.
>> It seems to come from people of the same
political persuasion. But
let's address this once and for all.
When she says that art has to mirror the
world that we live in, what she actually
means is art has to mirror the world
that she lives in. Like any good
activist, she wants and in fact needs
her art to reflect all of her political
views, reinforce her beliefs, justify
her world view. She doesn't really want
to be challenged or presented with
alternative ideas because the prospect
of any other perspectives being given
artistic credence and therefore
legitimacy is so terrifying to people
like her that it simply can't be allowed
to happen. Only one particular world
view is ever
>> That's why they try to go out of their
way to attack anybody who is right-wing
inside of media because if you have
right-wing media or entertainment that's
popular, it destroys the, you know,
seeming moral, like majority that they
have. This is why they go after anybody,
like they they do like these tribunals
to make sure that people say, "Are you
saying BLM? Are you saying free
Palestine? Are you saying X, Y, or Z
thing?" Like they do that in order so
that in order for them to enforce
compliance. It's the same reason why
women get really angry at other women
whenever they date men that women don't
really necessarily approve of in mass.
It's because basically they want to act
as one collective bargaining force and
they know that their ability to do that
is how they can express power.
allowed to be advocated for and that
version has to be hammered home in every
aspect of people's lives so there's
literally no choice but to conform.
That's the very obvious motivation
behind the all art is political
argument, but even if you set aside the
self-serving bullshittery of it all,
it's ultimately grounded in a flawed
premise. The reality is that art is not
inherently political. Art is
entertainment and entertainment exists
outside of politics. It always has. From
paintings and poetry to movies and video
games, all of these different artistic
expressions exist for the same basic
reason, to entertain us, to engage us,
to pass
>> I think that I I actually don't think
this is a good argument.
I think that on a fundamental level, the
way that you tell a story is politically
charged.
And I think that even inside of stories
that are seemingly apolitical, nine out
of 10 of them, and probably a higher
ratio than that, actually do have
political DNA in them. And I think that
you can reverse engineer that DNA to
look at the messaging behind the story
and what the political affiliation of it
is. I I I do think that's true. Like
whether it is even just something as
simple as an appeal to tradition or
something about a woman being able to,
you know, do something that a man can
do,
or whether it's something like the
police that are able to go above and
beyond and work extrajudicially to go
after a criminal even though they might
have broken some rules, something like
Sicario, for example.
Like I actually think that many things
are, you know, you could easily say
they're political. Like Taken, you know,
is a movie, like in a way that's
political because it shows that the
government in a lot of cases doesn't
actually do these things and it requires
a man to go out of his own way and to
enact vigilante justice and to, you
know, do the right thing because he's
presented as a hero and it's an evidence
of the system that's failed. So, I
actually think that you shouldn't argue
on the angle of politics isn't art isn't
political. I think you should argue on
the element of your art and your
politics is garbage and nobody likes it
or wants to have anything to do with it,
rather than trying to make an argument
that I think is defeating itself. Where
like even Tolkien himself said that Lord
of the Rings is a profoundly Catholic
work. And what is Catholicism? I think
it's very closely related to politics
because politics is informed by
religion. So, the reality is that yes,
art actually is political, and it's not
about whether art is political or not,
it's about whose politics is being
reinforced.
That's really what matters.
Commercial entertainment is not art,
although it can approach that at the
cost of commercial success. Well, you
have things that are always like again,
like there's a spectrum of it, and what
I'm saying is that there are more than
there are more things than you would
imagine that are actually on that
political spectrum.
That's all my point is.
It has political elements, but it's not
political in its totality. Yes.
I think there's a huge spectrum.
Time with a pleasant little distraction.
Is The Warriors 1979 movie political?
Absolutely, it's political. Abs- it
a 100% The Warriors is political.
Like that that that's like one of the
easiest ones that you can say.
>> We don't need art to survive. We create
it and we consume it because we choose
to, not because it's a necessary
reflection of our own worlds. In fact,
I'd argue that a lot of people consume
entertainment specifically to escape
from the real world, and who can blame
them? It provides a welcome distraction
from the tedious humdrum reality of most
people's daily lives. It can elevate and
inspire. It can open windows into
fantastical alien worlds and far-off
futures we can barely comprehend. It can
expand the limits of our world and our
imagination, and it can do and be all of
these things independent of politics.
Yes, art can absolutely explore
political themes if that's the express
objective of the art in question, but
>> And I think that overwhelmingly most art
does explore political themes and
overarching themes that are Venn
diagrams with political ideologies.
I think that overwhelmingly almost all
art does that. Batman is, again, the
entire genesis of what Batman is, for
example, is all about the idea of what
happens whenever the police don't do
their job and you need somebody who is a
vigilante that's able to do that job for
them.
Like that's that's really a Batman was a
Chad. Yeah, exactly. It's a question of
justice and and these things are not
they're not directly political in the
same way that vote for Democrats is
political. But they do encourage thought
about conversations that lead to
political conclusions.
And I think that's a good thing, by the
way.
That's an amazing thing. It's not a bad
thing. It's good because it makes shows
interesting because politics and the way
that we interact with the world is
political.
The Joker is anarchy is an
anti-capitalistic. Yeah, the Joker is
obviously anarchy, right?
It's order against anarchy.
>> It's not a prerequisite for its
consideration as a piece of art and it's
definitely not required for it to be
entertaining. What Tatiana here
narrow-mindedly thinks of as politics in
art are actually the much broader, more
interesting and universal fields of
philosophy and morality.
>> Yes. Politics is just a very specific
very limited interpretation of those
things. They are not the same and trying
to conflate the two by crowbarring very
specific and very partisan themes into
stories and setting
>> I I think that they're they're
derivative. Like they're derivative of
each other. Like politics is derivative
of philosophy and philosophy is
derivative into politics.
Like there's I mean they're they're they
they feed into each other.
>> Things that absolutely shouldn't
accommodate them is exactly why
mainstream entertainment is in the
creative slump it's been for the past
decades. It's also the reason Sydney
Sweeney's tits somehow became a national
emergency. When you try to make all art
political and those politics are only
ever allowed to go in one direction.
>> social politics.
Her expressing and showing her body that
way is absolutely social politics.
>> You don't have art anymore. You've got
[__] propaganda. You might want that
Tatiana, but the rest of us don't.
Ultimately though, I have to defer to
Oscar Wilde on this one when he said,
"It is the spectator, not life, that art
mirrors." People extract meaning from
art independent of what the creator
intended and what precisely they extract
says more about them than the art
itself. If you choose to see politics in
everything and you insist that art has
to mirror that worldview, then [__] me,
man. Maybe you're the problem.
>> Yeah, and you're trying to you're you're
trying to insert your worldview into
everything.
>> Anyway, that's all I've got for today.
Go away now.
>> I think this is a good video and I I do
think that he's very right about the
fact that a lot of media and a lot of
actors think that it's their
responsibility to talk about politics,
but I feel like again, after the Harvey
Weinstein stuff, it was just over. It's
over. Nobody wants to hear from an actor
about what the good or the right thing
to do is from now on. It's annoying.
Nobody wants to hear about it. I mean,
it's just too much, right?
And yeah, there it is. All games and
movies are just propaganda now. Well,
there's thinly veiled propaganda that
are inside
There's There's thinly veiled propaganda
that's inside of video games, right? So,
like things like for example, changing
male and female to body type one and
two. This was done for a political and a
social political reason. And so, the
problem is that these people want to
worm their politics into everything and
I think that really the best way to
approach that is to fight fire with
fire. You do have to replace people like
that and you have to go after them and
basically replace their ideology with
your ideology. Because again, there
isn't a world where this is never
approached by anybody. There's only a
world where there's a dominant ideology
and a subservient ideology. So, I don't
agree or believe that like you can just
kind of it it's like what I always say
about like it it you know, you can never
leave the gun on the table. It's either
you pick it up or somebody else does.
So, that's the way I look at anything
else. And uh thinly veiled Yeah, it it's
it's very thinly veiled, but that's it.